Malik Hantash Nadeem

131 – D1 Block Johar Town, Lahore, Pakistan +923074587539 <u>Hantashnadeem@gmail.com</u> <u>https://www.linkedin.com/in/hantash-nadeem/</u>

Professional Summary

Motivated, focused, experienced Android Developer having almost **5 years of experience**. Having multiple Android Apps on Google Play Store.

Proficient in object-oriented design, problem solving, complexity analysis, testing, debugging and troubleshooting. Experienced in working individually and within a team.

Experience

SOZIE Limited - Main Boulevard Gulberg, Lahore

Senior Android Developer

July 2020 – Present

- Direct communication with clients.
- Responsible for working in all phases of the project including design, development testing and deployment.
- Continuously discover, evaluate, and implement new technologies to maximize development efficiency.

ATPM Techno - Main Boulevard Gulberg, Lahore

Android Developer

August 2018 – July 2020

- Design and build advanced applications for the Android platform.
- Responsible for converting applications written in iOS into Android.
- Work on bug fixing and improving application performance.

Linez Technologies - Faisal Town, Lahore

Junior Android Developer

Feb 2017 - June 2018

- Collaborate with cross-functional teams to define, design, and ship new features.
- Ensure that apps are tested to meet total performance requirements.
- Work on bug fixing and improving application performance.

Education

BS. Computer Science Cumulative GPA: 3.37	University of Lahore	2012 - 2016
Intermediate (ICS) Percentage: 70%	Elite Science College	2010 - 2012

Professional Skills

- Experience with Java, Kotlin, Flutter, Jetpack, Navigation Component, Coroutines, Material Design, Google Maps/location, Firebase APIs/FCM, Web Services, REST API, JSON/GSON Parsing, SQLite database, Services, Broadcast Receivers, etc.
- Architectures: MVC, MVP, MVVM
- Libraries: Volley, Retrofit, ButterKnife, Picasso, Glide, Data Binding, RxAndroid, Dagger 2

Projects

1. SOZIE

This app helps different clothing brands to create real experience or feedback for their customers

Technologies: Kotlin, MVVM, Data Binding, Dagger 2, Coroutines, Material designs, View Pager 2, Retrofit, Restful API, Firebase, etc.

URL: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.sozie.sozieapp

2. Al Yasat Auctions

An auction company in UAE. It allows users to bid on available products.

Technologies: Kotlin, MVVM, Data Binding, Dagger 2, Material designs, Retrofit, Restful API, Google Maps, GPS Location Data, Firebase etc.

URL: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=ae.atpm.auction

3. TipTapGo

Allows users to send a tip to anyone using this app.

Technologies: Java, MVVM, Data Binding, Dagger 2, Material designs, View Pager 2, Retrofit, Restful API, GPS Location Data, Firebase etc.

URL: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.mercedes.net

4. Infinite Disc Golf Scorecard

This app provides a simple way to find disc golf courses to play and can record your round scores.

Technologies: Java, MVC, Material designs, Retrofit, Restful API, Google Maps, GPS Location Data, Firebase etc.

URL: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.linez.tech.infinitediscgolf